Guide to the Laura Chen-Schultz Collection on Asian Working Artists MC.369
New York University Archives
Laura Chen-Schultz Collection on Asian Working Artists
1997-2005
New York University Archives
Chen-Schultz, Laura
MC.369
2 linear feet in 4 manuscript boxes
30 videocassettes (vhs)
4 videodiscs (dvd)
Laura Chen-Schultz is the Deputy Director of the Asian/Pacific/American Institute at New York University, where she works to preserve and share community histories. In the late 1990s and early 2000s, Chen-Schultz served as the staff liaison for Asian Working Artists (AWA), a student group active at the Tisch School of Arts. AWA, founded in 1997, consisted of undergraduate and graduate students across multiple disciplines interested in creating community amongst sutdent artists of Asian and Pacific descent. The group held general meetings and social gatherings, attended theatrical productions, hosted lectures and screenings of works by guest artists, and managed an online discussion list. The Laura Chen-Schultz Collection on Asian Working Artists (dated 1997-2005) consists of materials collected by Chen-Shultz documenting the activities of Asian Working Artists. Materials in this collection include administrative documents, as well as flyers, posters, and other ephemera documenting the organization's events, particularly Asian Film Night and Java House. The collection also includes video recordings on VHS and optical disc submitted for Asian Film Night.
Scope and Contents
The Laura Chen-Schultz Collection on Asian Working Artists (dated 1997-2005) consists of materials collected by Chen-Shultz documenting the activities of Asian Working Artists, a student organization active at the Tisch School of the Arts at New York University. Materials in this collection include administrative documents, as well as flyers, posters, and other ephemera documenting the organization's events, particularly Asian Film Night and Java House. The collection also includes video recordings on VHS and optical disc submitted for Asian Film Night.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically into two series:
Series I. Administrative Records
Series II. Video Recordings
Conditions Governing Access
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Laura Chen-Schultz in May 2023; the accession number associated with this gift is 2023.045.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Video recordings are not available for playback. Researchers may view an item's original container, with the exception of containers with personal student information written on them.
Biographical Note
Laura Chen-Schultz is the Deputy Director of the Asian/Pacific/American Institute at New York University, where she works to preserve and share community histories. In the late 1990s and early 2000s, Chen-Schultz served as the staff liaison for Asian Working Artists (AWA), a student group active at the Tisch School of Arts. AWA, founded in 1997, consisted of undergraduate and graduate students across multiple disciplines interested in creating community amongst sutdent artists of Asian and Pacific descent. The group held general meetings and social gatherings, attended theatrical productions, hosted lectures and screenings of works by guest artists, and managed an online discussion list.
Appraisal
A duplicate recording of Hello Kitty is Dead on an optical disc was appraised out of the collection.
College students -- New York (N.Y.); Student activities.; Asian American art.; Asian American artists.; Asian American college students.; Asian American mass media; Asian American motion picture producers and directors.; Asian Americans and mass media; Chen-Schultz, Laura; Asian Working Artists
- Series I. Administrative Records, 1997-2003; .5 linear feet in 1 manuscript box
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of administrative documents, as well as flyers, posters, and other ephemera documenting the organization's events, particularly Asian Film Night and Java House.
  - AWA Administration, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AWA Awards, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AWA Event Calendars, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AWA Events and Screenings, 1997-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AWA Film Night, 1999-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - AWA General Meetings, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AWA Java House, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AWA Student Life Club, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ephemera, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Tisch, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II. Video Recordings, 1997-2005; 1.5 linear feet in 3 manuscript boxes
  This series consists of video recordings on VHS and optical disc submitted for Asian Film Night.
  Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
  Video recordings are not available for playback. Researchers may view an item's original container, with the exception of containers with personal student information written on them.
  - Aamala, undated (Box 2, Item 369.0001)
  - Air, undated (Box 2, Item 369.0002)
  - Anomaly, 2004 (Box 2, Item 369.0003)
  - Chutney Popcorn, 1999 (Box 2, Item 369.0004)
  - Coma, 1998 (Box 2, Item 369.0005)
  - Edible Women, 1997 (Box 2, Item 369.0006)
  - Émigré, undated (Box 4, Item 369.0031)
  - Family Auburn, undated (Box 2, Item 369.0007)
  - Family Recipe, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0008)
  - Gauze, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0009)
  - Ginseng Dreams, undated (Box 2, Item 369.0010)
  - Girl from Mile 9, 2001 (Box 3, Item 369.0011)
  - The Glass Ceiling, 2002 (Box 2, Item 369.0012)
  - Happy Day Naom, undated (Box 2, Item 369.0013)
  - Hello Kitty is Dead, undated (Box 2, Item 369.0014)
  - Rich Kiamco Demo DVD, 2005 (Box 4, Item 369.0032)
  - La Porn Opera, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0015)
  - A Letter Home / A Question of Time, undated (Box 2, Item 369.0016)
  - Life of a Janitor, undated (Box 4, Item 369.0033)
  - Little India, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0017)
  - It's About That Time: A Turntable Sonata, undated (Box 4, Item 369.0034)
  - Name, Age, and Occupation, undated (Box 2, Item 369.0018)
  - No Sex and the City, 2002 (Box 3, Item 369.0019)
  - Out of Time, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0020)
  - Pinching British Buns (and Colonial Order), undated (Box 3, Item 369.0021)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0022)
  - Sonny's Journey, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0023)
  - Troposphere, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0024)
  - A Waiter Tomorrow, 1998 (Box 4, Item 369.0025)
  - What's Love Got to Do With It?, 2002 (Box 4, Item 369.0026)
  - Tisch School of Arts Animation Compilation, undated (Box 4, Item 369.0027)
  - The Best of the Julie Gaw Show, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0028)
  - Untitled Video Recording, undated (Box 3, Item 369.0029)
  - Untitled Video Recording, undated (Box 4, Item 369.0030)